<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>

        <title>Helping Hallie</title>
        <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/</link>
        <description>Helping Hallie</description>
    
    <item>
        <title>Hallie Update</title>
        <author>Necia Munro</author>

        <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

        <guid>1307037600</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <description>
<![CDATA[
<p>This month has been filled with appointments, tests, and more appointments. We are doing tests to get her ready for surgery on her tethered spinal cord. We are doing tests to figure out why her reflux is so bad (she is on iv meds for it 2x a day and is maxed out on them). We are doing tests to determine if we have to do surgery on her neck. On top of that, add our monthly GI and Pulmonology appointments and Hallie ended up with a sinus infection. So, we started her on antibiotics, which helped the cough that aggravated her asthma. However, it also killed off too much of the good bacteria in her intestines and she ended up with an intestinal infection.</p>
<p>It has been a rough few weeks for Hallie. We also went to Nauvoo, IL for my sister in-law's wedding and then to Kentucky for her reception. It is eye opening to see how hard it is on Hallie's body to travel like that. The day of the wedding, Hallie felt so horrible that I had to pull her wheelchair out. All she wanted was to be held. Unfortunately, my body is so sore from holding her all of the time, that I just can't do it for very long. It hurts her to be moved around too much while she is like that and she gets really nauseated because of the pain. The best way for her to cope is to sleep, but when that isn't possible it is to be in her wheelchair, that minimizes her being moved around. The reception was the next weekend, and while all of her infections were cleared up, traveling still takes its toll on her body and she ended up playing in a classroom at the church all by herself most of the time and threw up all the way back to the house after because her head hurt too much. I hate seeing how much her life is being limited by all of this!</p>
<p>On the good side, this has been a much better week! Her body isn't fighting any infections, so she is waking up with a smile on her face. It doesn't always last very long, but it is so nice to start off each day on a good note. And she isn't screaming at night, which means that I sleep much better and am in a much better mood to start the day. I am continually amazed at how her body copes with everything. She lost 2 lbs in 2 weeks due to the intestinal infection. It was so frustrating to see because it takes us so long to put that kind of weight on her. But withing a week and a half, she has gained it all back. Despite all of her pain and discomfort, she is still managing to gain weight. Her GI doctors are slowly weaning her off of her IV nutrition. What an incredible blessing that is! She has been on the TPN for 2 years now. We tried taking her off of it last summer, but they did it a lot more abruptly and it landed her in the hospital. They are being a lot more cautious this time, slowly taking out the lipids, and then reducing the calories, and this week they are reducing the fluid. We will hopefully reduce the fluid one more time in a few weeks and then take her off of it. I am nervous, but also very excited to see what Hallie does. It gives us a lot more freedom to not have her hooked up to iv's all of the time. She still is on her iv meds for her reflux, which means that she still has to have her port accessed twice a week, but we are hopeful that we can start cutting back on that soon as well. Her reflux has never been this bad, with her needing this much medicine to prevent her reflux from aggravating her asthma. But hopefully, with summer finally here, her lungs will recover quickly from all of the respiratory illnesses and won't be as easily flared up. If we can cut back on her iv reflux meds, it gives her a few days a week when her port isn't accessed, which means there is nothing outside of her body. She can then bathe and swim and pretend to be a normal kid a few times a week.</p>
<p>We will finish up Hallie's tests next week. She has a CT scan and MRI scheduled for Monday. She does have to be put out completely for the MRI, but we are really hoping to not have the same violent reactions she has had the last couple of times. This mom cannot keep dealing with that and Hallie feels so horrible after the medicine wears off about how she acted. I have pulled her medical records and found out they used the same drug both times she reacted so negatively. So her neurosurgeon added that to Hallie's black list of drugs she can't take (she is allergic to 4 kinds of pain meds, almost all tape and dressings-- hers get shipped in from Sweden) and now this anesthesia drug). This will be our trial run on a different drug to see if she reacts the same before going in for surgery. It is very important that she not thrash around after spinal surgery, so we really hope she doesn't react the same way, otherwise she will have to be kept sedated after surgery, in the ICU, until the anesthesia wears off. Hallie's last MRI found a new senistivity. They brought her out without her hospital gown on because wherever the gown touched her skin turned flaming red. They have given me a gown to bring home and wash here, since she doesn't seem to react to the detergent I use and we hope that helps. In typical Hallie fashion, she told our home health nurse, with all confidence that her Grammy would make her her very own hospital gowns. She wants one that is pink and chocolate in color and one with rainbows all over it. Poor Grammy!</p>
<p>Once the tests are done, we have to meet with the urologist. She is being somewhat difficult and won't schedule an appointment until after we get the MRI results. Don't ask me what the bladder function tests and the MRI of her brain have anything to do with each other, since the MRI is to look more at the problems in her neck, but she absolutely refuses to schedule us unil after that point. It is very frusrating because we can't schedule the surgery for her tethered cord until after we meet with the urologist. The neurosurgeon finally took pity on me and scheduled us to see her on the 16th, in hopes that it will put pressure on the urologist to put us in on the 13th. If she doesn't, we can only get the results of the scans from the neurosurgeon and find out if we have to do surgery on her neck. We would then have to go back after meeting with the urologist to schedule the surgery for the tethered cord. What a pain! We are really hoping to get in to see the urologist before our appointment with the neurosurgeon so that we can get all of the results and schedule whatever needs to be done in the one appointment. We are so tired of waiting. It is so hard to watch her suffer when we finally know what is causing her pain, but not be able to fix it just yet! We know she needs surgery and are just anxious to get on with it.</p>
<p>Hallie is funny about all of this. I was tucking her in one night and her legs were hurting her a lot. She looked at me and told me that they had better do her surgery on her back before her 6th birthday (December) because she is planning on growing a lot when she turns 6 and it will just make her hurt even more. Another morning, she woke up and told me that if they didn't do her surgery before her birthday, she wasn't going to be very happy. It amazes me what a good attitude she has about it all. What an incredible example she is to me!</p>
<p>The last few months have been really hard on me. I have Hallie, with all of her needs and then I have 2 kids and a dog with Tucker's had ear infections again (his tubes fell out) and Carson has been at the doctor a few times as well. I will be so glad when school is out next week! I am so tired of trying to fit homework and everything else in amidst all of the doctors and everything else Hallie needs! We have been very blessed with our family stepping up to pick up the slack with the boys. Tucker spent a week with Grandma and Grandpa in Kentucky and our dog stayed with them after the wedding. Carson is going to Utah for a month to stay with his cousins and have some semblance of a normal summer. The rest of us will be going for a quick visit the end of June, into July. We need to get back so that they can get moving with Hallie's surgery, but we are excited to spend a little while with family and our amazing support system in Utah.</p>
<p>Thank you all for your continued support. We never dreamt that Hallie would go through so much and yet every time we find out something new that is wrong, you all lift us up and help us continue going. We very much appreciate it!</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Hallie Update</title>
        <author>Necia Munro</author>

        <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

        <guid>1304638200</guid>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2011 18:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <description>
<![CDATA[
<p>I have to say that for the first time in a really long time, I feel really good about the direction we are heading in with Hallie. I met with her neurosurgeon today. She was absolutely phenomenal. I have found that it is extremely difficult to find doctors that are good with kids and that know their stuff. You can find one or the other, but both in the same doctor is amazing. Dr. Bowman was all of that and more. We were there for about 1 1/2 hours, talking and going over everything. But instead of asking me questions about Hallie's history that is already in her computer, she focused more on the quality of Hallie's life. She asked me questions that no other doctor has asked me about. It was such a good feeling!</p>
<p>She told Hallie that there were 3 rules in the clinic. Hallie was not interested in hearing them, until the doctor shared the first one: We eat junk food here (accompanied by a bag of animal crackers and one of gold fish). The second rule was: We watch movies and the final one was that kids don't have to do the boring work-- parents did. She sent Hallie into the room next door to watch a Cinderella movie with her snacks while we got down to business. It was so nice to be able to focus on what the doctor was telling me, without having Hallie interrupt every 2 minutes to ask why the nurse is wearing a pink shirt. There have been many appointments when I have known that I needed to focus on what the doctor was saying and wished that I didn't have to bring Hallie with.</p>
<p>I was able to see her MRI images. The bottom portion of Hallie's spinal column is filled with fat. She has fat no where else in her body, but evidently has it stored in her spinal cord. It is pushing on her nerves and hiding a tethered cord. The doctor told me that normally she isn't supposed to make a decision about whether to do surgery or not without doing a full work up, but in Hallie's case, she absolutely deserves to have it untethered. We still have to get the other tests run, but we will be doing surgery to repair it.</p>
<p>A tethered cord is a form of Spina Bifida, so this is a huge diagnosis. We have been working on state assistance and they wouldn't approve her, but this diagnosis alone changes that. They are requesting the records from this appointment and once they confirm the diagnosis, Hallie will be approved for state assistance for anything related to her tethered cord. What a huge blessing this will be! We still have many other expenses, but this will be a huge relief!</p>
<p>Hallie needs to have an MRI done of her brain, meet with a urologist, have a muscle tone test, and also a CT of her neck. The MRI shows mostly soft tissue, so they didn't get clear details, but they saw enough that they know the C1 and C2 vertebrae are abnormal. Her doctor suspects that they are fused, which brings a whole new set of complications. The CT of her neck will show a lot more detail of her bones. It's still too early to say if she needs surgery on it, but we did talk about that possiblity. The two cannot be corrected at the same time, so if the neck needs to be fixed, it is more urgent, as those vertebrae hold up the head. She would have that surgery first and then about a month later, have the one for the tethered cord.</p>
<p>We are hoping to get all of these tests done in the next 3 weeks or so. We will then meet with her neurosurgeon and decide if she needs both surgeries, or just the one. The one for the tethered cord will probably not be done until July. We will also be meeting with a genetecist to try and figure out what has caused all of Hallie's birth defects. Now that we have these new problems, hopefully, it will point us in the right direction. They feel like Hallie has some syndrome that hasn't been diagnosed that has caused all of her problems. They are all too rare to occur by chance together. If we can figure out what has caused it all, we will know if there are any other problems we should be looking for.</p>
<p>Thank you all for your support. We have had a rough few months and couldn't have done it without you. We are hopeful that by the end of summer, Hallie will be doing much better, but regardless, we know that whatever comes our way, we can deal with it because we have a great support group! We have several fundraisers that are in the works for the end of summer and fall and will keep you posted on the details. If any of you have great fundraising ideas, please let me know!</p>
]]>
        </description>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Hallie Update</title>
        <author>Necia Munro</author>

        <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

        <guid>1303528200</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2011 22:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <description>
        <![CDATA[
        <p>What a crazy month this has been-- one I hope to never have to live through again. Hallie has been in so much pain lately. She is missing 1-2 days of school a week because she just doesn't feel well enough to go. Her whole body is hurting. It is mostly her head, belly, and legs, although lately she has been telling me that her entire body is hurting. She is sleeping more frequently, needing either a nap or bedtime at 6:00 almost every day. It is so devastating to watch her suffer day in and day out. Hallie's poor body is so tired and she is emotionally exhausted. I wake up a lot of mornings to her screaming at about 5:30 and it doesn't stop until she finally crashes. She is starting to suffer from depression and has told us that she just doesn't want to be alive anymore. She is so tired of hurting and we are emotionally drained just watching her suffer like this.</p>
        <p>We were finally able to get Hallie's biopsies done last week. I feel like we have waited a lifetime to get them done, seeing how we had to reschedule it due to her asthma flare up last month. The surgery itself was successful, although Hallie reacted negatively to some of the drugs she was given and woke up very angry and violent. She was ornery until she saw me and then turned out right violent. We had to pad her bed and they wanted to restrain her. I finally had hold her in a bear hug with my legs wrapped around her for over an hour so that she didn't hurt herself. I had to call her daddy to come to the hospital to help. Part of it is the drugs, part of it may be her depression, and part of it is that she just doesn't like me right now. Hallie loves me, but doesn't like me so much. She views me as the one that is forcing her to go to the doctors and hospital and take her medicines. She thinks that I can just decide to be done with it and it will all go away. It is so hard to deal with her and make sure her needs are being met and yet she is so dependent on me and smothers me most days. Hallie was pretty sore for several days after surgery, but in typical Hallie style, she was up and running as long as she had some medicine in her. She may or may not have over done it for a few days.</p>
        <p>We had her meeting this week to set up her care plan for going to kindergarten. It is so hard to believe that we are to that point. I don't let myself think too far into the future with her because it is so unknown. I haven't let myself think too much about what was beyond preschool. I have been very impressed with the school district here. We had a meeting with her preschool teacher, director of the preschool, and the nurse at the preschool, as well as the kindergarten teacher, principal, school nurse, and resource teacher. They were very willing to accommodate her needs and help in her transition. We walked away feeling very pleased with the results. We will have another meeting 2 weeks after school starts to reassess whether they are meeting all of her needs. It's a little difficult to determine what all of her needs are when it is still months away before school starts, so I am happy that we will be meeting again to re-evaluate everything.</p>
        <p>Yesterday, Hallie had her MRI. They had to put her under completely, and once again she reacted violently when she woke up. They finally kicked us out after she had stayed the minimum required time after anesthesia and it took 3 of us to get her dressed. It took 2 of us to get her out to the car. It was quite the scene. I am sure we gave a lot of people a whole lot to talk about. I had to put her in my 2 year old's car seat so that I could use the 5 point harness to restrain her. It was not pretty. Then I got a phone call from the department of specialized children's needs in Illinois telling me that basically, Hallie needs are not special enough to get any kind of assistance. I am so frustrated! We are trying to get respite nursing because Hallie is completely wearing me out and the only thing they can offer me is a facility I can drop her off at for a weekend once in a while. That isn't an option I would even consider, unless it is a dire emergency. After that, I got the information on our new insurance that begins in July and I am more than nervous about it. All in all, yesterday was a pretty rough day.</p>
        <p>This morning, I got a phone call from Hallie's neurologist-- the same doctor that told me that her pain may be psychological a few weeks ago. Her MRI shows several areas of concern. They were not able to rule out a tethered spinal cord, but they couldn't diagnose it definitively. There are, however, abnormalities that typically go hand in hand with a tethered cord. With a tethered cord, the nerves at the end of the spinal column are connected at the bottom. Typically, they are hanging free, to allow for movement and growth. As a child grows with a tethered cord, it stretches the nerves tighter and tighter, it can cause problems with the way messages are transmitted along them. It can effect most areas of the body, although bladder and bowel issues, as well as balance problems are the most common ones. I have suspected a tethered cord for some time. It took me awhile to convince doctors to test for it, but I am so glad that I did!</p>
        <p>They also found some abnormalities in the vertebrae in her neck. It appears there are two of them that are stuck together. This could be the cause of her debilitating headaches. The neurologist referred us to a neurosurgeon. We will go see him on May 5. Hopefully, we will have a lot of answers and a definite plan to move forward with.</p>
        <p>There is a part of me that breathed out a huge sigh of relief this morning. At least they found something. Hallie has had so many tests done only to be told that she is "normal". It is so frustrating to know that your daughter is suffering immensely and not be able to find what is causing it. I feel like I have been caught in this nightmare, begging for help, only to be told time after time after time that there is nothing wrong that they can fix. If this MRI hadn't shown anything, I honestly don't know where we would have gone from here in terms of figuring out what is causing all of this pain. So I am very relieved to have an answer and be moving in the direction of helping her, not just watching while she suffers.</p>
        <p>On the other hand, I am so scared. I have been sick to my stomach all day. I don't know much about either abnormality, but I do know that they both have the potential of needing to be fixed through neurosurgery and that both surgeries carry a risk of paralysis. I know that risk is small, but (unfortunately) I have gotten somewhat comfortable with bowel surgery. I know what to expect both for the surgery and the recovery after. Neurosurgery is a complete unknown. I am anxious to meet with the neurosurgeon and figure out where we go from here. They have a tethered cord clinic down town that has all sorts of different specialties that work together to treat kids with this condition. What a huge blessing that is!</p>
        <p>Over all, I am so humbled. It astonishes me to see how many seemingly unrelated birth defects Hallie has. And yet, she is fighting and doing well, all things considering. She told the nurses at the hospital yesterday that she was coughing in hopes that they would cancel the MRI. So underneath the depression and pain, I know that my little girl's spunk and feisty attitude is still there and it is good to see that there. I don't know what Hallie's mission on earth is, but I do know that it is only through the grace of God that her little body is able to function. When I start to itemize her birth defects, I know that she has a very special mission and nothing will cut her time here on earth short, unless it is God's will. I am in awe that I was chosen to be her mother. There are so many times that I feel so inadequate to navigate through her needs and doctors and everything else. She is absolutely incredible and I am so blessed to be her mother.</p>
        <p>The next few weeks are going to bring a lot of big decisions for Derrick and I to make on her behalf. Please pray for guidance for us and that we will know what to do to give her back her quality of life. So many have stepped up to support us through these trying times and we are so grateful for it. From babysitting (no small task when I need help 3-4 times a week), to the meals, to the cute flowers a friend of Hallie's brought over, they have all helped to lift our burden and make it more bearable. And a huge thank you for the monetary donations. They have been a huge blessing, especially this month. I am finding out each and every day how incredible a support system we have and what amazing, selfless people we have in our lives. Thank you all!</p>
        ]]></description>
    </item>

    <item>
        <title>Hallie Update</title>
        <author>Necia Munro</author>

        <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

        <guid>1300834800</guid>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2011 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <description>
  <![CDATA[
    <p>Where do I begin? We started off March with a trip to her cardiologist. Her heart problems have been a non-issue for years, but with all of the other problems cropping up, her doctors wanted us to be sure that there weren't any other problems going on that we weren't aware of. Her cardiologist was very intrigued by Hallie. He even performed her echocardiogram himself. He found some interesting things-- not anything to be hugely alarmed about, but just add to our list of things to watch. She has been diagnosed with heterataxia. Basically, it means that all of her major organs are in the wrong place. Her heart is in the middle of her chest, instead of on the left. It is also rotated, so it is hard to get a clear view of it. He can't say for sure if her whole has closed, but if it hasn't, it is not causing any major issues at this point. Her liver is midline as well, instead of on the right side. We knew it wasn't shaped right and is very flat, but we didn't know it wasn't in the right place. Overall, her cardiologist was astounded that she is doing so well with all of her birth defects. He said that after reading her records, he anticipated seeing a very sickly child, barely hanging on to her life. The nurse practitioner was very complimentary and told me that we were doing a phenomenal job. She says that she always worries sending a baby home from the NICU if the parents are going to be able to care for it. She told us that if she knew all of them would care for their children the way Hallie has been cared for, she would worry a lot less. I think sometimes we get so wrapped up in all that is wrong with Hallie that it is nice to be reminded that while she does have all of these problems, she is doing as good as she possibly can with them all.</p>
    <p>After cardiology, we went for an ultrasound of her major organs. What was supposed to be an hour test turned into two hours when the ultrasound tech saw how complicated Hallie's organs are. She about had a coronary when I asked her how many of Hallie's spleens she could see. She could only find 4 of her 5 spleens. The ultrasound further confirmed her heterataxia diagnosis. The radiologist was fascinated by how misplaced her organs are and how the blood supply is so different, but seems to be working just fine. They didn't find anything major wrong, but just more things to keep an eye on because with heterataxia, there are a lot of complications that can happen.</p>
    <p>Hallie's pulmonologist was very please with how well she was doing in the lung department, so she gave the go ahead to take Hallie of her iv protonix, which helps control her reflux. Hallie's asthmas is exacerbated by her reflux, so we have found that if we can keep the reflux under control, we can keep the asthma under control. I wasn't loving the idea of pulling her off of the protonix, but agreed since we now have a pulmonologist watching her so closely and have started her on several new medications to keep it under control. Unfortunately, 2 weeks ago she started coughing. We started her on the action plan, increasing her albuterol and doing it through the nebulizer, since it responds best to it. After a few days and no improvement, they had us start her on steroids. They've helped, but haven't cleared it up. Hallie was supposed to have surgery yesterday to take biopsies of her intestines, but they were not comfortable with doing it with her cough. I had her to the pediatrician Friday to make sure we didn't have a secondary infection (she didn't although Tucker had 2 ear infections). Her lungs were clear and her pulmonologist cleared her for surgery, but the anesthesiologist was on a power trip and refused to do it. Her surgeon was willing to go ahead if we wanted to but after dealing with the anesthesiologist, the last thing we wanted to do was have him be in charge of keeping our daughter alive during the surgery.</p>
    <p>So they cancelled the surgery. It is beyond frustrating. Unfortunately, Hallie has more than one system that has problems and it is a constant balancing act to deal with all of her needs. There are times that the benefits to one system far outweighs the risk to another. She has had surgery with a cough several times. It is not something we do lightly, but she is absolutely miserable. Her home nurse looked at her yesterday and told me how worried she is about Hallie. Her body is so tired of fighting. She asked me this morning to get her wheelchair out. We haven't had to use that since before we moved here. Hallie has always been this vivacious, energetic "normal" child that has medical issues to deal with. She rarely has let anything stop her. Even if she does have a bad morning, she is back to her normal self, pushing through the pain so that it doesn't control her life. She is changing her outlook to more of that of a chronically ill child that is struggling to live a normal life, but whose illness is getting the better of her far too often. It is heart breaking to watch. As hard as all of this has been, we've been able to hold on to the fact that she isn't letting it stop her and enjoy watching her be as normal as she possibly can be. It is so hard to watch her medical problems slowly getting the better of her. Last night, she started with a migraine. She moaned and groaned all of the way through dinner. She went to bed early, hardly able to keep her eyes open. This morning, Hallie woke up needing pain meds by about 5:45. Her belly was hurting her. By 8:00, we were back at the pulmonologist and while the pain meds helped, she still was hurting. Her head hurt, her belly hurt, her legs hurt (something that is happening with increasing frequency). I had to carry her into the hospital to see the doctor. Even through the appointment, she wasn't herself and after, I wasn't sure she would be able to go to school. Hallie finally pulled herself together as I dropped her off and really seemed to enjoy school, but still is just not herself.</p>
    <p>Where do we go from here? I am really pushing her doctors to find the answers to that question. We are putting her back on her iv protonix to get her reflux under control. We had her down to only a few doses a week, but I think we are going to do it daily to get her asthma under control. As soon as the cough clears up, we will take her back in for the biopsies, hopefully in about 2 weeks. I've spoken with her neurologist and with all of her symptoms, especially the leg pain and she has had a lot of balance issues lateley, we are going to do an MRI to check for a tethered spinal cord. What that means is that the nerves at the end of the spinal column are attached and as she grows, it is pulling those nerves tighter and tighter, causing a lot of problems since the message is not always getting through clearly. It would explain ALL of her symptoms. There is a part of me that is so hoping that is the problem because even though it would require a neurosurgeon to go in and fix it, it would alleviate the majority of her problems. On a more practical side, I know that it is not likely that is the problem because honestly, how many different problems can a child be born with? But then again, Hallie has never listened too closely to the odds, so I am holding out a sliver of hope. The MRI has to be done sedated, so we can't do it until her cough clears up. They are pushing to see if we can get it done at the same time as her biopsies. The hospital doesn't like doing it that way since they have to transport her sedated from one floor to another, but we have both the neurologist and GI doc pushing for it, so we shall see.</p>
    <p>Next week is spring break and since my in-laws came and got Tucker, the older 2 kids and I will be driving to Kentucky on Friday and staying next week. We need a break from all of the medical stuff, so we are really looking forward to it. Not to mention that with Grandma and Grandpa, that is a lot more help for me and I may have a chance to keep my sanity!</p>
    <p>A huge thank you to all of you who continue to help us through this. I can honestly say that this is harder than I ever thought anything could be. There are days that I wonder how in the world we are going to get through it all. But in the end, when I am at my lowest, there is always someone stepping up, helping to share our burden. Whether it is a kind comment, a meal brought in, babysitting, or help fundraising for her ongoing expenses, it all helps us get through this step by step.</p>
    <p>Please keep our friends the Larson family in your prayers. They lost their sweet Brady yesterday. He was close to Hallie's age and while they suffered from different things, it was always nice to connect with his mom, whom I grew up with, and share our experiences and what we have learned works and doesn't work with these special needs kids. Brady's passing, while not unexpected, hits very close to home for us and our hearts are aching for his parents.</p>
        ]]></description>

    </item>

      <item>
        <title>Hallie Update</title>
        <author>Necia Munro</author>

        <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

        <guid>1296840600</guid>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2011 11:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>I typed up this whole update day before yesterday and then the internet went out and I lost it all. So we will give this another try. Hallie was admited to the hospital on Monday. She was in increasing pain and eating less and less. With the blizzard coming, we felt it was in her best interest to admit her for a few days to try and figure out what was going on. She spent more time in the radiology department on Monday than any where else, having x-rays and contrast studies.</p>
        <p>Tuesday morning, they started the x-rays again at 6:00 a.m. It was a very long day. They did irrigations every 4 hours in hopes of removing the obstruction. Hallie's intestines are so far from normal that it was very painful for her. I think that is the most pain she has been in, aside from intestinal surgery. It was very difficult for both she and I. Derrick was in Vegas on business, so luckily his dad was able to come and stay with the boys. Tuesday afternoon, the blizzard hit. It was very odd being in the hospital with a skeletal staff. One floor only had 2 of 25 nurses show up. Our poor nurse worked a double shift. The boys did great and only lost power for a few minutes. We ended up with about 20" of snow in less than 24 hours.</p>
        <p>Wednesday they woke us up at 5:00 for x-rays but couldn't do the contrast study ordered until the radiologist was able to get in. We got in for the study late morning and it came back normal. The obstruction was completely gone. So I guess all of the pain from the day before was worth it to not have to go through another surgery, but I hope to never have to do another day like that again! Driving home was interesting. The snow had stopped but the city was still digging itself out. I don't think I will ever drive on that deserted of streets in Chicago ever again. It was quite the experience.</p>
        <p>Hallie is back at school today. You would never guess that she was just in the hospital. In true Hallie style, she was out playing in the snow yesterday with her brothers.</p>
        <p>Moving foward, I was able to vent a lot of my frustrations to her GI team. I feel like she has these episodes, but I'm not sure if it is because of there being no consistency in care, or us being so far from her doctors, it seems like they are discounting how frequently they are happening. The doctor I was talking to had spent all last week pouring over the 350+ pages of her medical records and said she was astonished to see how frequently she is in the hospital. We are hoping to figure out what keeps causing these episodes and work on either preventing them or managing them better so that she doesn't hurt as much. She meets with a neurologist next week to try and figure out her headaches. It's possible that whatever is causing those is contributing to her GI issues. The next week she sees the pulmonologist because she is of course wheezing. I am trying to get them to look at her body as a whole and not just each individual system. Her GI issues aggravate her asthma so we can't change her reflux meds without consulting pulmonology. She is seeing cardiology in a few weeks. If her heart problems are still present, they could be contributing to both her headaches and GI problems. We are looking to put an entire team together that will communicate amongst themselves and hopefully give us a better overall picture of what her body is doing.</p>
        <p>I am off to see the ENT for my 2 year old Tucker for his chronic sinus infections. Incidentally, we found out he needs to have surgery to repair his droopy eyelid before it changes the shape of his eye and he has vision problems. Why not-- although hopefully, it will be several years down the road.</p>
        <p>Thank you all for your support through all of this, both the kind thoughts and prayers and those that are closer that brought in meals and dug us out after the blizzard so that Hallie and I could go home. It seems never ending, our hospital stays and doctors visits and I don't know how I would get through it without the support system the Lord has blessed us with.</p>
       ]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Hallie Update</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1296309600</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 08:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>Hallie has had a rough couple of weeks, at least in comparison to how well she has been doing. It was very subtle to begin with-- she began sleeping more frequently, taking naps, going to bed early, waking up late (she NEVER gets up late--we are lucky to have her sleep until 7:00). She started having quite a few horrible headaches, but not necessarily abdominal pain. She started to get dark circles under her eyes. I was concerned enought that I called her doctor. I have to give them credit in that they took these minor things and ran with them. I have had doctors brush me off with such small signs and wait until bigger ones show up.</p>
        <p>They sent Hallie for an x-ray last week. It is our typical first line of defense to see what is going on and typically we don't see much from one. We got a phone call telling us that the report showed dilations (the bowel stretching out), but we weren't sure if it was really an issue until they were abe to actually compare the x-ray to her previous ones.</p>
        <p>I got a phone call yesterday asking me to bring her in for further tests. They were a little hesitant to tell me what their suspicions were, but seeing how I have been down this road more than a few times, I knew what to ask. They think she has a partial obstruction. This is what she had in March of 2009 that required surgery to repair. She has been in a lot more pain this week and even missed a day of school. She woke up yesterday at 5:30 needing pain meds.</p>
        <p>I'm concerned. In our experience, if it shows up on an x-ray, it typically leads to surgery. We have been assigned to a transplant surgeon, which at this point just means that she is part of the intestinal rehabilitation program, but definitely could mean that she may become a candidate down the road. He has reviewed all of her medical records (they were pretty shocked at how extensive they are) and has been brought up to speed on Hallie. Dr. Suprina will review the tests and help make a decision on where we go from here.</p>
        <p>This is going to be a tough week. Between my 3 kids, I have 7 appointments in 5 days. 6 of them are on Monday-Wednesday alone. My father in-law is coming up to help me out, thank goodness. My church is bringing in some meals so that I don't have to worry about that. As for the rest of you, we are asking that you please pray for Hallie and her doctors and family. The tests are exactly pleasant. We need the Lord's hand in guiding her doctors and us in making the decisions that are best for Hallie. We will keep you posted as we find things out. This is not a true emergency, since she is still functioning. We may not find out what is really going on until Friday. But we will keep you posted as we hear anything. Thank you all for your on going support.</p>
       ]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Hallie is 5!</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1293640200</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2010 12:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>Amidst all of the chaos of moving and Christmas and everything else, Hallie turned 5. Each birthday with her is a huge milestone, not something we take for granted. And she is celebrating big time by doing better than she has in 2 years. Her intestines are working really well right now, she is being slowly taken off of TPN and takiing oral meds to get her ready for that time. She is taking in all of her fluids by mouth and is eating really well. What a great birthday present! The intestines grow between age 5-6, so we are hoping that this continued improvement will be a long term thing.</p>
        <p>Hallie was accepted into the high risk preschool program here, which will start preparing her for the school system and the school system for her. She tested off the charts for her cognitive development, so they are trying to set up things to challenge her, as well as preparing for what they need to do to take care of her while she is there. We are waiting to hear back from the doctor that oversees the program as to when she starts, but we are hoping it will be sometime in the next few weeks. She is so excited and can't wait to get back to school and neither can I!</p>
        <p>On the down side, I took my kids into the dentist yesterday and Hallie's teeth are a mess. I guess the combination of medicines as well as the frequency of her vomiting over the last few years can soften the enamel. It doesn't seem fair that she has to deal with all of this, but she is a trooper. They wanted to have it done at a hospital and put her under because she will possibly need a root canal, but because of the side effects on her intestines, we are choosing to attempt it in the office. If there is a problem, we will move to the hospital, but we feel like with all of the procedures she has had done and the risks to all of her other systems, it is best to try it without all of the other meds first. My oldest son has to get early orthodontic intervention and he is thrilled, so Hallie thinks it's going to be great. We shall see how she does!</p>
        <p>All in all, Hallie is doing amazing. She continues to fight with a strength that amazes me. Her immune system is getting stronger. The rest of the family has been antibiotics for a cough we couldn't get rid of, but Hallie got over it very quickly. We couldn't ask for her to be doing better and we are so happy to have this respite!</p>
      ]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Hallie Update</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1291834800</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2010 13:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>Life has been so busy lately! We made it to Chicago about 3 weeks ago. We are really loving it here! It has been such a good move for all of us. I love Hallie's new GI doctor! It is so nice to have a GI team to help deal with everything. We have a social worker and a dietician, as well as 2 nurse practitioners and the doctor. They have taken a huge load off of my shoulders. We have a pediatrician as well, that I already got to take our youngest to for a sinus infection. The pediatrician is 5 minutes from our house. They are working on getting all of Hallie's specialists in place for us.</p>
        <p>Hallie has a preschool assessment on Monday for the high risk program. In Illinois, if a child is considered to be at risk for missing a lot of school or falling behind, they will actually pay for them to attend school and have therapists on site to work with them. Hallie is supposed to be going to physical therapy to help with her pain, so this would be a great set up for her. It also sets the foundation for how they will deal with her in the schools, once she starts kindergarten. We are really excited for this and are praying that she is accepted to the program.</p>
        <p>For right now, Hallie's body is functioning well. She is on very little medication. We are cutting back to 3 days of iv nutrition a week. It has been a huge blessing as we have been moving. I prayed that she would be stable enough to get us out here and she has far exceeded that. The last few days have begun a bit of a downhill slide, so we will see what she does from here, but we are incredibly blessed to have had her doing so well for the last little while.</p>
        <p>Things are very different working with an established GI dept. I am used to having more say in things, so it will be an adjustment, but I am hopeful that it will be for her good. They will admit her for at least 72 hours for a fever over 100.4. It doesn't take much for her to spike a fever like that, so we are hoping and praying that she stays as healthy as possible this winter. If not, we could be seeing a lot of the children's hospital!</p>
        <p>Thank you all for your continued love and support and most importantly, prayers. I took Hallie with me to the pediatrician this morning and the doctor was shocked by how well Hallie looked. After hearing her history, she was expecting a child that was in much worse condition. Most are amazed at how well she does with the severity of her problems. It defies medical reason and can only be attributed to a loving Heavenly Father working His miracles. Please pray that He will continue to bless her with the strength that she needs to get through these challenges.</p>
      ]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Big Changes</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1286915400</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2010 13:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>We have a lot of big changes coming in our life and we are very excited about them. We are moving to Chicago in about a month. Derrick has been offerred a transfer within his company. He will travel less, have better hours, have a better salary, and most important, they have 7 children's hospitals in Chicago for Hallie. I will no longer have to travel for her care!</p>
        <p>Life is pretty chaotic right now, as we are getting ready to move. I was talking to Hallie's dietician this morning and when I told her the move was a for sure thing, she started asking a lot of questions. When we started talking about how many doctors and therapists that I need to find for Hallie, she commented that moving that distance is stressful enough, but to have to move with a child like Hallie is very complicated. Luckily, we have been assigned a case manager through our insurance that is helping me make all of the arrangements.</p>
        <p>So while it is crazy and a ton of work, we are so excited for what this means for our family. Above all, it will provide more stability for the kids, especially our boys. My in-laws live about 5 hours away and have offered to come up and take care of the boys any time Hallie is sick or in the hospital. They will be able to stay in their own home, in their own beds, regardless of what Hallie needs to have done. It is an answer to every one of our prayers and then some! So ready or not, Chicago here we come!</p>
      ]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Hallie Update</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1285190100</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2010 14:15:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>Once again, Hallie and I are back from Salt Lake. I kind of feel like a yo-yo-- back and forth. She had surgery last Tuesday to put her port back in. We actually had the uncomplicated version this time around! Her surgeon had a veinogram done before we left the hospital last time to see exactly where all of her veins run and which would be the best one to put another line in. Because of her polysplenia, none of her veins return to her heart normally, so it makes things all the more challenging. Luckily, they got the port in on the first time!</p>
        <p>They also gave her a steroid following surgery to help with asthma (her reflux causes her asthma to kick in) and it helped a lot. Her bowels recovered quicker following surgery and she was HUNGRY for about 3 days. She even woke up at 4:30 one morning asking for chicken noodle soup. It was a huge blessing because Hallie's PICC line got a hole in it the weekend before we were supposed to get her port replaced. We weren't able to use it and they weren't able to repair her PICC like the hoped to. It is best to let the site of the port heal up for about a week before you use it, so the original plan was to keep her PICC in for about a week after the surgery to allow us to give her the TPN. Unfortunately, they had to pull the PICC and I really didn't want them putting another one in for just a week. She was able to eat so much the first few days following surgery that she didn't require any supplements. It was really nice. I was also able to do tube feeds into her stomach at night after that because the steroid had calmed her bowels down so much. It was a huge blessing!</p>
        <p>Unfortunately, it is not safe to use the steroid for chronic problems, so it is not a long-term solution for her. The last couple of nights, she has not tolerated her tube feeds very well. I had to have a difficult conversation with her dietician yesterday about what she is truly capable of. Hallie has now been on TPN for a year. We started out at 3 times a week, then after a few months went to 5 days a week. We did that for about 6 months and then were able to pull her completely off for a few months. She has been on TPN for 7 days a week since July. When you see it spelled out like that, it isn't hard to see that despite our best efforts, she is declining. Her intestines are capable of less and less. It is so frustrating to see her like this, to not be able to do anything to halt her downhill progress. I would love for her to stabilize, even if it is at the point she is at now.</p>
        <p>Everything is such an uphill battle. On the outside, Hallie looks and acts normal. I get so frustrated when people tell me she looks good. I have to work so hard to keep her out of the hospital, that it is disheartening for people that know us and her, make that comment without acknowledging how sick she really is. At the airport, every time I asked for early boarding, people gave me really wierd looks and I would have to explain the situation. I've heard her condition and other similar ones called the silent illness and I completely understand why. Most people will never understand how much she has to go through on a daily basis in order to stay alive. It is hard to explain to people how sick she really is because she looks no different that most other children.</p>
        <p>Despite having to come to grasp with her downhill progress, I have to say that we are extremely blessed. I have no doubt of the Lord's hand in our lives, helping us through these difficult times. Every time, I get discouraged or upset, I don't have to look very far to find people that have it worse than we do. I don't have to look far to see the many blessings in my life to help balance out the challenges. We have found a new foundation to pay for Hallie to fly to her many doctor's visits. That is huge in our world! We have more people now, than at any other time in Hallie's life organizing fundraisers on her behalf, regardless of where they live. Quite honestly, I don't have time to work on fundraisers when I am so busy taking care of Hallie and trying to take care of my boys as well. What a blessing to have money coming in that I don't have to stress about!</p>
        <p>We are trying to simplify our lives right now. I am going through our house deep cleaning and weeding out things that we really don't need. We are cutting out things that don't need to be in our lives because they cause too much stress and headache. We are always looking for ways to make our lives easier in order to balance Hallie's needs better.</p>
        <p>We are very excited because we have a lot of family coming into town this week for our oldest's baptism. Derrick's parents and brother are flying in tonight, my youngest brother and his family are coming in tomorrow night, my parents and sister as well as my middle brother and his family are all coming in on Friday. Everyone leaves on Sunday, which will be sad, but my mother in-law will be staying for an extra week to help me out while Derrick is out of town for work. We love having family come visit and especially enjoy the help we get while they are here!</p>
        <p>Hallie is meeting with a pain specialist next week to try and manage her pain better. I have been through 6 Tylenol with codeine prescriptions in the last 2 1/2 months. We will be very glad to have some other alternatives to help in that regard. She is loving dance and preschool, which in their own way provide her with a natural pain med. She is able to focus on the things she wants to and forget for a little while the pain she lives in every day. We are very grateful that she has found these avenues to explore and be excited about.</p>
        <p>Thank you for your continued support. It truly means a lot to each of us!</p>
      ]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Hallie Update</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1283468400</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2010 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>Hallie and I are home. We flew in on Friday and have spent the last 5 days trying to adjust and catch up on life at home. Hallie will finish hope her antibiotics tomorrow, which will give her 5 hours a day that she is not hooked up to her PICC line and means that we won't have to wake up in the middle of the night to give her meds. We will be very glad to get through tomorrow! Hallie and I will be flying back to Salt Lake on the 13th. She is scheduled for surgery to put her port back in on the 14th. It should be outpatient, although last time they almost ended up admitting her because of complications. We are really hoping for the non-complicated version this time, although knowing Hallie, she likes to do things the hard way, so I won't be surprised if she ends up spending the night.</p>
        <p>Hallie is starting dance today. She is so excited! We are trying to give her as normal of a childhood as possible and give her some positive things to hold onto through everything else. I think she is a little confused, though, because yesterday she was practicing cheers to be ready for dance. Tomorrow she meets with her preschool teacher and she will start school on Tuesday. There are lots of new things beginning in her life and we are so excited to be able to watch her enjoy and explore life, just like other kids.</p>
        <p>Thank you all for your continued support.</p>
]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Hallie Update</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1282629600</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2010 23:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>After 9 days, Hallie is finally out of the hospital. We ended up having to pull her port on Saturday. She was so funny because after surgery she was so ornery and mean that I finally asked her what was wrong. She told me they gave her the wrong medicine. I asked what medicine and she told me the angry medicine. Surgery went fine and as soon as we pulled the infected line, she started having clean cultures, so we were able to put a new line in. She cannot have another port for a month in order to give her body a chance to recover before placing another one, so we put a PICC line in (for those than don't know, they put a catheter in the vein in your arm and thread it up to empty right above your heart). We will need to return in a month and have the port placed and the PICC removed.</p>
        <p>Hallie is amazing. Through all of this, she has sang and danced, skipped and hopped all over the hospital. People would ask if she was really sick. Yes, she was really sick, although I don't think it hit me how sick she really was until we got discharged from the hospital today. I feel like we took half of the pharmacy with us. She is on 11 different medications, quite a few of them through the iv. What a complicated mess it was to organize everything with the home health and regular pharmacy. I still am missing quite a few things that I need for her, so I had to start making lists to remember it all. I had to sit down and make a schedule of when she needs what meds in order to keep them all straight and make sure we get them all in. Hallie will be on iv antibiotics for 2-3 weeks. Wow! That is a really long time for antibiotics, especially ones as strong as these ones. She is on other meds to try and help her intestines stay healthy through all of it, so we don't get a different infection as well.</p>
        <p>Tonight, as I put her down to bed and saw how pale she is, it really struck me how blessed we are to have her. She motivates me on a daily basis and inspires me to be a better person. So while I may be overwhelmed and glad that I don't have to add my boys back into the mix for a few more days, I am so incredibly grateful to be able to have Hallie sleeping in my room (I have to get up at 3:00 to give her some antibiotics) and to see evidence of what an amazing angel the Lord has entrusted to me.</p>
        <p>Thank you all for your prayers and kind words and thoughts. This hospitalization we have felt a huge outpouring of love and support, unlike any other hospital stay. It has made a huge difference and we are very grateful for all of you.</p>
]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Home Again...</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1281322800</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2010 20:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>We are back home and hope to stay here for a while. Hallie ended up in the emergency room in Salt Lake Tuesday morning. She had eaten something that did not agree with her intestines and it caused immense pain. She just kept crying that she couldn't do this anymore. It was heartbreaking. After about 5 hours of it, and numerous times throwing up, I finally gave in and took her to the ER. We were there for 6 hours before her body got it all out of her system and they discharged her. I had maybe an hour of sleep at this point, Hallie had maybe 3 hours. We got back to my mom and dad's and all I wanted to do was crawl in bed. Luckily, my father-in-law had flown in and gotten my boys that morning to take them back to Reno. I tried to convince Hallie that we needed to sleep, but she wasn't believing it for anything. She had a soccer practice to go to.</p>
        <p>This was the highlight of Hallie's trip. My sister plays soccer for Alta High. They had conditioning and try outs while we were there. It started as my mom taking Hallie with to pass out popsicles at the end of each practice and by the end, they were pulling Hallie into their circle for their team cheer. I am so grateful for these coaches and girls that took Hallie in. They gave her something to look forward to each and every day (and sometimes twice a day). She was able to fight through her pain because she HAD to be to practice. Thank you for letting Hallie be a part of something other than fighting for her life. You will never know how much it means to her and to us! We had to stop by on Friday as we were leaving and the team gave her a soccer ball that they had all signed. She even has a team bracelet that she can't take off because the coach told all of the girls to always wear them.</p>
        <p>Anyways, Wednesday, Hallie's needle came out of her port and they think some of her iv nutrtition infused into her skin. She has held her neck and head really funny since then. There is a fear of infection and everything that goes along with that, so we have been very concerned.</p>
        <p>Thursday, we took Hallie for her wheelchair fitting. I have to say this is one of the highlights of my trip. We met with the wheelchair specialist and with a physical therapist. They understood her needs so well, it was kind of eerie. Normally I have to explain things over and over to get things done, but they just got it. The wheelchair specialist's husband had his colon removed and a portion of his small intestines. The physical therapist totally understood everything we talked about and I think we are really going to be happy with her chair. We went with an adapted stroller, which is a cross between a wheelchair and a stroller. It will recline so that on those days that she just isn't feeling well, she isn't stuck in a 90 degree position. And most importantly, it will be pink. She is so excited! We have a loaner one until they get the insurance to authorize and ship us our real one, and while it doesn't have all of the features hers will, I already am loving it!</p>
        <p>Friday we headed home and she did fairly well. It was kind of strange to make the drive with my husband, Hallie and our dog. Derrick was able to meet up with us after about a week for a show he had to do in Salt Lake. We are very happy to be home and even happier to have our family back together again.</p>
        <p>Yesterday, Hallie started throwing up again and started with a fever. I'm hoping this is just a virus, but with everything else, you just can't be sure. Thank goodness she is back on her iv nutrition because at least I can keep her out of the hospital. Last night she was so sick, so I started her iv nutrition a little early. Within 30 minutes, she was feeling better because she actually was getting nutrition. I hate that she needs it and is on 7 days a week of it, which is the highest she has ever needed since she was 6 months old, but I am so grateful that the technology is available that we can keep her alive with it. Hallie really isn't eating much of anything, so it is really nice to be able to get her the nutrition that she desperately needs.</p>
        <p>We never know what the next week will bring, but for tonight, I am enjoying my kids, celebrating my Tucker's birthday and grateful that for at least right now, Hallie seems to be feeling better. She even ate part of a hamburger bun for dinner.</p>
]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Hallie Update</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1280728800</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2010 23:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>Hallie finally seems to be on the up swing. She hasn't needed pain meds for a few days, and we are slowly increasing what she can eat. We add a new food every day to see what she tolerates. It is a very slow process, but she seems to be doing well with it. She is back on iv nutrition, so she is getting stronger every day. We are hoping to get back to Reno by the end of the week, after a few more appointments. Thank you all for your continued prayers and support!</p>
]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Hallie Update</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1280291400</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2010 22:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>What a crazy few days it has been! Hallie was admitted to the hospital Friday night with another bowel obstruction, but was stable enough to leave Saturday late afternoon. She has had a really rough couple of days, in a lot of pain and on a limited liquid diet. It has been extremely challenging. I took her back to Primary Children's yesterday and they put a tube down her nose into her intestines to inject contrast and see if she has done any damage. Hallie has had this test done at least 7-8 times in the last year and a half, but it just seems to get harder and harder each time. She was in so much pain that she was almost hyperventilating.</p>
        <p>Today I met with her GI doctor here in Salt Lake. The good news is that she hasn't done enough damage to her intestines to consider surgery at this point. The bad news is that she is so miserable that she yelled at the top of her lungs the whole time we were in there. I finally had to have my mom take her out so that I could actually carry on a conversation with the doctor. The plan right now is to try and rehab her from home, which we have already been doing. We are starting her back on iv nutrition because being malnourished can actually make these flare-ups harder to control. The radiologist says that she definitely has a pseudo-obstruction, where she has every symptom of an obstruction, without anything actually blocking the way. He says her bowels just look really upset right now. We will go back in for lab work on Thursday to see if there is any improvement. We are going to work more on pain management to try and get her more comfortable. We are going to get her a wheelchair because honestly, she is so weak and is hurting so much that she refuses to walk and I just can't carry her all of the time. That is a hard one to take because it just means that she is really sick. It's one of those things that on the outside, she looks fairly normal and you would never guess how sick she really is, but in a wheelchair, everyone would know it.</p>
        <p>I have talked to her doctors in Cincinnati multiple times and we are going to start exploring some new trial treatments beginning this fall and hope Hallie might be a candidate for it. If that isn't an option and she continues like she is, we will have to consider an ileostomy, where they separate her intestines and vent them out the side of her abdomen, where it would empty into a bag she would always have to wear. It is something that we have really been trying to avoid, but we are quickly running out of options.</p>
        <p>She is far from stable enough to travel back to Reno this weekend, as planned, so my father in-law is flying in from Kentucky and will be flying to Reno with my boys. I will stay behind with Hallie at my parents until she is well enough to go home. Honestly, she is more than a full time job right now, so it will be nice to know that my boys are being well taken care of without me feeling like I am neglecting them. Tucker's 2nd birthday is 10 days away, so I am really hoping to be home with him for it.</p>
        <p>Thank you all for your words of encouragement and support. I am so grateful for the support system that we have because this is by far the hardest thing that I have ever had to do. We appreciate you all!</p>
]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>In the Hospital</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1279949400</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2010 23:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>Hallie is in the hospital here in Salt Lake. Last week, she had what they thought was a pseudo-obstruction. All of her x-rays were showing improvement, but her bowels were just not functioning right. Add to it her pain and I have been very concerned. I was planning on leaving this morning for Salt Lake anyways, but when Hallie woke up at 2:30 this morning throwing up, I knew we were in serious trouble. I threw things in the car and hit the road with my 3 kids. After the 8 hour drive, I headed straight to the emergency room. Several hours later, they diagnosed her with a bowel obstruction and admitted her.</p>
        <p>Part of me is not surprised and has seen this coming. The other part of me feels caught in this awful cycle--been there, done that many times before. I know all too well what to expect and it makes me sick. In some ways, I wish I was the naive mom who didn't know anything. Unfortunately, I know what they are talking about when they say there is a possibility of doing an upper GI tomorrow and why they ask who her surgeon is. It breaks my heart to know what is ahead for her, and while no one has said that surgery is necessary, I know her body well enough to know that it is likely. I hate having my family torn apart, although I am so grateful for my family that has my boys. I know that they are taken care of and it is a huge relief. I am anxious for Derrick to get out here next week, so that we can at least be in the same state.</p>
        <p>Plase keep Hallie in your prayers. She very much needs them right now!</p>
]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Thank You!</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1279315800</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 14:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>Thank you so much for all of your prayers! Hallie's x-rays this morning are dramatically improved-- more than the doctor would have guessed possible. She still has some issues, but they are hopeful that I can rehab her at home. We get to stay for the golf tournament! As long as nothing else goes wrong, we will be leaving for Salt Lake the end of next week, as originally planned.</p>
        <p>Thank you for all of your kind words and prayers!</p>
]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Please Pray for Hallie</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1279175400</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2010 23:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>Hallie has taken a drastic turn for the worse. It has gradually started coming on the last few weeks, but over the weekend, she was in so much pain, she couldn't even lay on her back. By Monday, the pain was out of control, so I took her in for an x-ray. It came back fairly normal, but with the pain, they had me put her on a clear liquid diet. Tuesday came and after working around the time difference and schedule differences of both her doctors here in Reno and her GI doctors in Cincinnati, we ended up at the hospital in the late afternoon for tests. Another x-ray, lab work, and an ultrasound. The lab work and ultrasound came back normal, but the x-ray shows a large amount of air in her intestines that wasn't there the day before. So today, add her doctors in Salt Lake into the mix, as well as our home health company and all I have done is spend the day on the phone.</p>
        <p>They are concerned that she has a bowel obstruction. My gut says that they are on the right track, but they want to give it a few more days to see if it is just a nasty virus that has hit her hard (Tucker just got over one) or if maybe by chance by not eating, it will decompress her intestines enough to clear any obstruction. In reality, they are trying to buy us time. Hallie's golf tournament is on Saturday and after working for almost a year on it, I would really like to be here.</p>
        <p>They have started her on pain meds (they NEVER do this except for post-op) and put her on iv fluids to try and keep her hydrated and eliminate as much as possible from going through her digestive system. I will take her in for an x-ray on Friday to see if anything has changed. Their hope is that the pain is decreasing and that there won't be as much air in her intestines. My hope is just that she isn't any worse than she is now. The plan is that as long as things remain the same, I will drive her to Salt Lake on Sunday (they do not want her flying). Of course, if she takes a downward turn, I will leave with her immediately, or admit her here and try to figure out how to get her to Salt Lake.</p>
        <p>This has come as a really hard blow for us. We knew that the likelihood of her having another obstruction was great, but we really hoped that with the new program she has been on, that we could buy her another year at least. I know all too well the signs and what may be ahead of us as we deal with this. We are understandably upset by this and jsut trying to deal with a 4 year old that is hurting and can't eat. Please keep us in your prayers. The next little while could get pretty rough. We need all of the help that we can get to help us through whatever may lie ahead.</p>
]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>iGive.com</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1278696600</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2010 10:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>Hallie has just been registered as a cause with <a href="http://www.igive.com/">iGive.com</a>. All you have to do is register on their website, selecting Helping Hallie as your cause. When you shop online through the website at hundreds of stores like Gap, Nordstrom, ebay, Amazon, etc., they donate a portion of the sales to Hallie. What a great way to raise money for her without any additional expense to you! If you want, you can also download their search bar and for every search you do, .01 goes to Hallie. It may not sound like much, but it can add up fast! Please take a moment and register so that iGive.com can start sending money to Hallie!</p>
]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Hallie Update</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1277343000</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2010 18:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>Hallie is staying off of TPN (for now). She has had a lot of ups and downs the last few weeks. When she is doing well, she eats great and gains weight. The problem is that her bad days are really bad and she loses a lot of weight on those days. I wass supposed to take her in for a weight check this week but "forgot" to. She's had more downs than ups and her weight hasn't been great, so I knew if I did, they would put her on TPN again for sure. She's had some pretty good days this week, so we are hoping that if we don't get the weight check until next week that she will be able to make up some ground. At least we will have a better idea of if she really needs to go back on TPN or not.</p>
        <p>She is loving not having her port accessed and having more freedom and she does seem to be tolerating her tube feeds better. On the other hand, she is consuming a LOT more formula and the insurance isn't paying for it at this point. We are having to pay over $800 a month just for formula! We are working with several different people to try and either get the insurance to cover it, or for the manufacturer to donate a few cases each month to help mitigate the costs. We are keeping our fingers crossed!</p>
        <p>Please find it in your hearts to help us out. Every little bit helps! Our last bill from Cincinnati was over $17,000!</p>
        <p>Thank you for your continued support!</p>
]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Hallie Update</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1276122600</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 15:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>Hallie is continuing to gain weight. She had about 2 weeks that were absoulutely amazing and then started having problems again. She is hurting a lot, but the good news is that she is still able to tolerate her formula feeds through her tube at night, so she is staying off of her iv nutrition for right now. If this continues, we will be removing her port in about a month. It is so nice to have her heading in a positive direction for a change!</p>
        <p>Thanks for all of your support and encouragement!</p>
]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Hallie Update</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1274846400</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2010 21:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>We just got back from Hallie's Make A Wish trip and it was AMAZING!!! They picked us up in a limo and took us to and from the airports. We stayed at a special village called Give Kids the World built specifically for kids like Hallie, fighting life threatening illnesses. Everything was free there. They had a carousel that ran all day; a spa that you could get your face painted, nails done, or airbrush tattoos; an ice cream parlor open from 8:00 in the morning until 10:00 at night; Boston Market brought in lunch and dinner to your individual villa; and Perkins Family Restaurant brought in breakfast and dinner at the Gingerbread House. The kids were able to go horseback riding, swimming, see Santa, as well as multiple characters that came to visit.</p>
        <p>On top of all of that, we went to Magic Kingdom, Animal Kingdom, Epcot, Hollywood Studios, and Sea World. We were given a pass that put Hallie at the front of every line, which made it even better. We had dinner one night with Cinderella, Prince Charming, the step mother, Anastasia, and Drisella. We also had dinner another night at Medieval Times.</p>
        <p>Hallie did really well our first day at the parks, other than throwing up on her cute outfit that she packed specifically for Magic Kingdom. After that, she really couldn't be pushed, so we spent 5-6 hours at the parks and then headed back to the Village for her to rest and us to be able to take part in their activities.</p>
        <p>We had a lot of family decide to meet up with us, so that added to the enjoyment. We had help! My kids loved being with cousins, aunts, uncles, and grandparents. It really meant a lot that they would all choose to come at their own expense to share with Hallie this special experience.</p>
        <p>Hallie had her ups and down throughout the trip. By the end of it, we had pushed pretty hard and all she wanted to do was swim. If that is one thing that we have learned from Hallie is how to adapt. When life throws you a curve, you learn how to make the most of it and go with it. But in the end, she was so happy. She has already asked to make a countdown chain until her next Disney trip. Her daddy told her that she might need a lot of paper for that one!</p>
        <p>Now on to even better news. When we came back, Hallie was really struggling with a lot of pain. I told her doctors that I couldn't continue forcing this medicine into her that wasn't helping and was causing such agony. So we had a conference call last week and bounced ideas back and forth with part of her Cincinnati team. We have changed up her medicine again, but this time, we seem to have found the magic combination. For the first time in over a year and a half, I am watching my daughter laugh and giggle, sing and dance. She is so HAPPY! We are able to control her pain so much better, with it really only surfacing about the time that she is ready for her next dose of meds (once a day). And even better, she is hungry. And not just a little hungry. She could probably eat a horse! I have heard her tell me that she is hungry more in the last 4-5 days than I have heard in the previous few months combined. It's incredible!</p>
        <p>I spoke to her Salt Lake doctors who monitor her nutrition today. Because she is eating so much better, as well as the fact that we took her off most of her iv nutrition while in Florida and she did well with it, they are taking her off of the TPN (iv nutrition). This is a huge step for her! TPN is very hard on the liver, so it is not something that she can be on indefinitely. We have worried over how in the world we were going to stop her downward spiral in which she needed more and more TPN. I kept telling her doctors that if we could just keep her stable and no more sliding down hill, I would be happy. We begin the weaning process today and let me tell you, I am ecstatic. I find myself in tears the last few days, watching the daughter that I thought was lost to me emerging again. She is a totally different child and I am so grateful for the miracle that has occurred to make it happen.</p>
        <p>I e-mailed her Cincinnati doctors yesterday after getting an x-ray (we have gotten 15 x-rays in the last 3 1/2 weeks), with an update. A short while later, I got a phone call from the nurse that I talk to on a daily basis. She was so excited and said that she had tears in her eyes as she read the email. The bowel management program was created for children that had malformations that prevented them from being able to learn how to control their bowels. Using it for a child with Hallie's problems was a stretch and it has definitely required adaptation. But she is one of their biggest successes! To think that not only is Hallie feeling better, but that because we were willing to go out on a limb with this treatment, that other children in her situation will be given the opportunity for the same treatment warms my heart.</p>
        <p>So I am finding myself with free time. It's a concept that is a little wierd to me. I have spent 2-3 hours a day for almost a month getting x-rays and then having them burned to a disc. I have done TPN and mixed it up and primed the pump, which takes 20-30 minutes on a good night. We have done that since September. We will keep her port in for the time being, to make sure that she really doesn't need it anymore, but I will no longer be accessing it, having to poke my daughter with a needle once a week. No more lab work once a week, which lately has meant me drawing her labs.</p>
        <p>Now I can focus on Hallie's golf tournament. Hallie has drained us financially. We have mountains of medical bills that we are struggling to pay. Salt Lake would like her back for some follow up visits. Cincinnati will want her back at some point this year to do a trial run of pulling her off of the enemas and see if her bowels are creating new nerve pathways. When the doctors have talked to us about needing to see her, I have wanted to ask them if they knew where I could get a money tree to plant in my back yard. Add to it that our insurance is changing in July and taking a definite turn for the worse (it's the worst insurance that we have had since having Hallie), it is very important that we have a successful tournament.</p>
        <p>For those that are here in the Reno area, we have a huge need for golfers. If you don't golf, come to the dinner and auction afterwards.</p>
        <p>We are looking for hole sponsors. This does not have to be a locals only thing. We have hole sponsors coming all the way from Kentucky. We have several families joining together to sponsor a hole.</p>
        <p>We are also looking for items to be donated for the auction or raffle. Once again, this does not have to be just a Reno thing. We have a lot of the same stores as most of you and gift certificates are great. My husband Derrick will be in Salt Lake for the next few weeks working and will be driving a truck back and will be able to bring anything back with him. My brother will also be bringing a trailer out with him for the tournament and is willing to bring anything with him.</p>
        <p>I have one final request. I don't think Hallie realizes how many people that she has touched with her story. We are compiling a scrap book for her to be able to look at and see how hard she has had to fight to stay here. I would like to include letters from those that she has touched. I have found that when I am struggling, if I look at the emails and messages that have been sent to me, it really helps lift my spirits. My hope is that this will work the same for Hallie. For those of you willing, please mail me the letter and perhaps a picture of yourself/family to <a href="mailto:contactus@helpinghallie.com">contactus@helpinghallie.com</a></p>
        <p>We have an incredible support system. I am so happy to be able to share good news with you, instead of just the hardships in our life. I thank the Lord for the blessings that you are in my life. I don't know how we could do it without you!</p>
]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Hallie Update</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1272130200</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2010 10:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>We just got back from Cincinnati yesterday. She was admitted for more tests for 3 days and then a week later, we met with her doctors for the results and a plan. We were very anxious to get Hallie out there as she was in a ton of pain. We even put her on a clear liquid diet for a few days to try and alleviate some of it. She would just lay there on the floor, refusing to move because it hurt so much.</p>
        <p>Traveling with Hallie is always difficult and we seem to always be on flights with delays or other problems with her. We got to the airport 2 hours early, but our flight out of Reno was going to be delayed so much that we were going to miss our second flight. It was so frustrating because we missed one of our flights the last trip to Cincinnati as a result of them not being able to guarantee our luggage would make it with us. We had a bunch of Hallie's medical equipment and medicines in it, so we couldn't take the chance of not making it. This time we thought we would be smarter and ship everything out the day before. So here Hallie, Tucker and I are sitting in Reno, with her iv nutrition sitting at grandma and grandpa's, waiting for us. They weren't able to get us in early enough that Hallie would have been able to get hooked up to her nutrition. She has to have a full 12 hours on the TPN and we weren't able to get into Cincinnati until midnight. We didn't get to my in-laws until almost 1:00 and she had to be admitted at noon. So, she wasn't able to have her nutrition that night, which was a huge thing because she couldn't have any while she was in the hospital for tests. I was very frustrated with the airlines for not trying to accomodate her needs a little better and try to get us in earlier to a surrounding airport. There are about 5 airports within a 2 hours drive and they wouldn't even look at flying us in to them.</p>
        <p>Anyways, Hallie was admitted and they started her bowel clean out. They put 1300 ml of the medicine into her stomach before anything started coming out, so she was in a ton of pain by evening time. She went down to surgery the next afternoon. What was scheduled to take 111 minutes, only took 36. I was concerned about what that meant, but the doctor said things went smoothly. She has so little of her colon left that they were able to get through it very quickly. Her colon is dilated, which could be contributing to her problems, but other than that, it looked good. They were able to place the manometery catheter to measure the pressure her intestines are able to exert. They even were able to get it part way into her small intestine, which was good. She was on a liquid diet on Wednesday and couldn't eat Thursday or the first part of Friday, which makes for some very long days. Some lady in the elevator gave her a little purse, so I started a food fund. Every time I was able to sneak out to get some food for me, I came back and put my change in her purse for her to get a snack when she could eat. I gave her a dollar when they took her back to perform the tests and she fell asleep with it in her hand. Friday, the started the manometry tests, which lasted 6 hours. It has 3 phases, the 2nd one allowing her to eat for half an hour. During the 3rd phase, they gave her medicine to encourage contractions in her intestines and it did its job well. She pushed the catheter part way out. We had some issues with the nurses and how they handled it, so I get to address that with the administrators.</p>
        <p>After she was discharged, we just hung out for several days, letting her start to feel better. She was extremely irritable and ornery and mean before we left for Cincinnati and the hospital visit didn't do much for that. Sunday, she kneed me in the jaw because I was trying to get her to wear a shirt that she didn't want to. She yelled and threw a fit for 45 minutes before I was able to calm her down and I walked out with a bruised jaw. Later that day, my mother in-law was making a salad to go with dinner. Hallie looked at the vegetables she was cutting and asked," Is that vegetables? I HATE vegetables!" She threw another fit for almost an hour over this one. My patience was pretty much gone by the time Derrick flew in Wednesday night. I told him that she was his for the whole 36 hours that we were going to be there together.</p>
        <p>We were able to go to the zoo, courtesy of the children's hospital, which was a nice break. She loved the animals and her little brother Tucker couldn't figure out how come there were so many "doggies" there. We visited family and got to spend time with her great grandma and a great-great aunt, as well as a visit from Derrick's cousin and her daughter that is just older than Hallie. It was nice to be able to fit some pleasure in.</p>
        <p>Thursday we met with the doctors. All of her test results came back normal. It's frustrating because at this point, we know something is wrong with her, so we just want them to be able to figure it out so that we can move forward with treating her. They called in a colo-rectal surgeon to meet with us. He was great, very complimentary of how Hallie's care has been handled so far. He said that just because her results came back normal doesn't mean that they believe she is normal. What a novel concept for the medical profession. So many of the doctors that we have dealt with would have seen normal and been content to not look further.</p>
        <p>They are enrolling Hallie in their intestinal rehabilitation program. We are taking her off all of her medicine, except for one (she will remain on the nutrition that she is on). She is starting on erithromycin, which helps stimulate the intestines to move faster. They think it will target the area that we think is struggling better than her other meds. She will also begin an enema regimen, getting one once a day for several months to try to teach her intestines how to function normally again. Every day next week, she will go to the hospital for x-rays to make sure that her bowels are completely emptying out and adjust the medicine as needed.</p>
        <p>I am overwhelmed at the thought of what the next little while will bring. They tell me to plan on about an hour a day to do al of her meds, on top of what I already spend doing her nutrition. Add into that all of the visits to the hospital next week and it is all I am going to get done. I'm hoping that it will be worth it, but you never know with Hallie, which makes it even more overwhelming. I am very happy with the doctors. Everyone else has pretty much been closing the door, telling us there was nothing more to be done for her, that it was a miracle she has made it this far. As a parent, that is very hard to hear. So for these doctors to have a plan, and not just one, but plan A, B, and C, it is an answer to prayer.</p>
        <p>We leave for Disneyworld in 2 weeks for her wish from Make a Wish. She is so excited she can hardly stand it. She keeps asking how many more "sleeps". My enthusiasm is curbed by the thoughts of how hard it is going to be to travel and for her to do something like that, as well as how to fit in an hour a day for meds, but I am hopeful. Mostly, I am just excited to have family time. We have extended family meeting us there and we are happy to get to spend time with them, but mostly we are just excited to be together with our family of 5. We have been torn apart so much the last year and a half, with me traveling with Hallie and Derrick having to work and Carson having to be in school. It will be like heaven to have all 5 of us together, enjoying something positive for a change.</p>
        <p>I came back with Hallie yesterday and while it was a nice change to only travel with one child and we even had a layover in Salt Lake, so we got to see my mom for about 45 minutes, I am still missing half of my family. I missed Carson like crazy this trip and it is so good to be back home. Derrick and Tucker will be flying home tomorrow and I cannot wait for that moment, when I have my 3 kids and husband back together. Tomorrow is going to be a good day!</p>
        <p>Thank you all for your continued prayers and support. Thank you for those that have called and sent messages. They help carry us through the difficult times. Thank you for those that have donated to help with Hallie's expenses. They are astronomical and keep getting worse. It is a huge help to get the donations, even the small ones. It's one less co-pay I have to come up with and that is huge right now. Thank you for those that help me care for my boys while I am with Hallie. I don't think Carson really missed me because he had so much fun with the friends he got to play with while I was gone. And Tucker, well he is going to be one sad little boy tomorrow when he has to leave his "Papa". We could not get through all of this without the incredible support system that we have. The Lord does not give us trials to face beyond our capabilities. He usually places people in our lives to help make us strong enough to deal with them. So thank you all for being a part of our lives and helping us through Hallie's journey.</p>
        <p>P.S. Hallie would like to let you all know that she is going to be on the local news. We have a reporter coming out in a week and a half to interview us and hear her story. It will air in June, to help promote the golf tournament. We will make sure we get a copy and post it.</p>
]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Hallie Update</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1269124200</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2010 15:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>What a journey we have been on the last few weeks. It's literally been a roller coaster, full of ups and downs. Hallie had surgery to place her port in her chest 2 1/2 weeks ago. This was to replace her central line that broke. She came running in to me with blood running down her tummy, screaming when it broke. We were able to get it patched and left 2 days later for Salt Lake. The port was supposed to be a fairly simple surgery, but nothing is ever simple with Hallie. When her surgeon finally came out, he looked at us, shaking his head and said that he had forgotten how complex she is. None of her blood vessels route back to the heart normally. It makes placing these lines difficult because it is really a matter of trial and error. They had to try 3 times to get it in the right place and she lost a lot of blood in the process. We were anticipating her going home a few hours after surgery. 8 hours later, she was still struggling with pain and her oxygen levels. We were on the verge of admitting her, even though they had no open beds. She would have had to stay in recovery overnight. Luckily, they decided that she wasn't take deep enough breaths because of the pain. She is allergic to almost all narcotics, so we are very hesitant to give her much of anything. They finally decided that the risk of her getting RSV or whatever else was floating around the hospital outweighed the risk of sending her home with her oxygen being borderline. So off we went. She was hurting so much, it was hearbreaking. That is until her cousins brought her brothers home and then all of a sudden she could get off of my mom's couch and wanted to play. This has been her way since she was little. We can't do much pain medicine but when she is in a social environment, she is able to block out everything and just be the social butterfly she would like to be.</p>
        <p>While we spent the day at the hospital, I had a very open conversation with her surgeon. He basically told me that it is a miracle that she is still here. Her intestines were broken when she was born and they are still broken. There is no magical cure and even a transplant is extremely risky. He personally doesn't know of any survivors. This is as good as she is going to get in his opinion. It was very heartbreaking to hear. I don't think he told us anything that we didn't already know, but to have a doctor that knows your child as well as he does, spell it out in black and white, it is a tough reality to face. </p>
        <p>Her doctors at Stanford have told us that there isn't any more they can do for her, other than pain management and taking her off all food and having her be 100% dependent on outside nutrition. At this point, that is not even an option for us to consider. She has fought so hard that I can't give up and not continue to fight with her.</p>
        <p>Needless to say, we will not be returning to Stanford. We got in touch with another GI doctor in Salt Lake that we had seen when she was a baby. She has agreed to take Hallie on and ordered more tests for while we were there. The stuck a tube down her nose into her intestines, with the intent of putting contrast into her. Keep in mind that she is completely awake while they do this. It is very unpleasant and difficult to watch as a parent under normal circumstances. Of course Hallie didn't do it the normal way and her intestines completely rejected the tube. They couldn't get it in more than an inch or two after trying for 45 minutes. They tried to push some water through to see what her gut would do with it and she immediately threw everything up. The consulted with her doctors and decided to put 400ml through her feeding tube over 2 hours. This is a ton of fluid for her to process in such a short time and she was hurting so much! Mickey Mouse was at the hospital and we put her in a wagon to go see him. She didn't even care. She has developed a new coping technique where it is like she puts a wall between her conciousness and goes somewhere else. As a parent, it is extremely difficult to watch her do this. She just checks out and goes somewhere else. You ask her a question and it can take upward of a minute for her to process and respond, if she does at all. She did this both the day of her surgery and the day of her tests. For her sake, I am glad that she can do it and not have to feel all of the pain, but as a parent, it is incredibly difficult to watch. I thought that they had overmedicated her, but when she did it again with no meds, I knew that she was learning how to do it on her own.</p>
        <p>Anyways, Hallie got almost all of the fluid in and then threw it up. They decided to go ahead with the scan and hope for the best. We are still trying to figure out what the scan really shows. The radiologist feels like there is a build up of scar tissue along all 30+ incisions in her small intestine. The scare tissue is not necessarily blocking the intestines, just not allowing it to move properly. Her surgeon feels like it looks about the same as the one that she had done last year and he is not worried about it.</p>
        <p>It's so frustrating to try and figure out who to listen to and where to go from here. My gut instinct is that the radiologist is right. I've talked to Cincinnati about it and they have arranged for her to come back to see them next month. She will be admitted for 3 days for further testing, in hopes of confirming what the radiologist saw. We will have to remain in Cincinnati for 11 days so that we can let the doctors review the results and meet with us. We are anxious to get there, even though it will only be Hallie, Tucker and I. Derrick and Carson will be remaining behind, although Derrick is hoping to be able to come out for the last few days to meet with the doctors.</p>
        <p>As Hallie's expenses are growing exponentially, it is so important for her golf tournament to be a huge success. If any of you have contacts that would be willing to sponsor or know people who are golfers, please give them the information about her tournament. The registration form as well as a letter are on her website www.helpinghallie.com.</p>
        <p>We have also had quite a few people ask us if we are doing the yard sale again this year. The answer is probably, but we will be doing it differently. It was far to large to do at our house, so we are looking for somewhere else for us to host it at. It could be a warehouse, a store front, a church, anywhere with a large space that we could go in on a Monday, set up tables and clothing racks, have people donate items all week in which we will sort, price, and put out. That way, come the day of the sale (Friday and Saturday), it is all ready to go. If any you know of a place that we could hold it at, please let me know.</p>
        <p>Thank you all for your kind words and especially for those that are stepping up and helping with my boys. It means the world to me to have them taken care of while I am dealing with Hallie.</p>
]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Hallie Update</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1267047000</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2010 13:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>Life has been chaos the last few months. We moved and very happy to be settled into our new house. It makes caring for Hallie so much easier! Her medical supplies are organized and easy to find and it is so much easier to keep germ free so that she doesn't get sick.</p>
        <p>I live at the doctors anymore. That or the pharmacy. Our 18 month old little boy had his adenoids out on Monday, so we are really hoping that cuts down on some of our visits. Hallie has been wheezing for almost 4 months now. We have tried everything. We can get it to clear up, but we can't get it to stay clear. We get to go see an asthma/allergy doctor in a few hours. She gets to have an allergy test done and we are hoping to figure out what is causing all of this.</p>
        <p>We took Hallie to Stanford a few weeks ago and were not pleased with what they could do for her. They basically told us that there wasn't anything else they could do for her. They can try and control her pain through accupuncture, hypnotherapy, and psychotherapy, but there might come a time when we would want to take her off all food and put her 100% on TPN. It was extremely difficult to hear, especially when I have other doctors telling me that we still have options, so we will not be taking her back to Stanford. Our mindset has changed from what can we do to help her to we can't live with regrets. I can't look back down the road and wonder if we had continued to look for treatment options, if it would have made a difference in the outcome.</p>
        <p>Cincinnati has sent her case to their surgery department to have them review. They told me they hoped I wasn't upset by including more people in her team. I told them the more the merrier. If they can come up with an idea of how to help her, I would be thrilled. They are trying to figure out if there is anything that they can do for her that would warrant us heading back out there. I am so impressed that they are willing to continue looking for options and answers for us, even though they really aren't getting paid for it. They are driven by the challenge and I am so appreciative of it!</p>
        <p>In some ways, Hallie has improved a little. She no longer has the constant headaches and her belly pain is no longer constant either. She has her moments when she can be the normal 4 year old little girl that we wish she could be. In other ways, she has gotten worse. I'm not sure if she is on too much medicine, if she is just trying to assert her control over our lives, or if there is something more going on. She has started to have accidents again, which she hasn't had in well over a year. It is pretty much every day. As parents, we are so frustrated because we thought we were past this. Logically, I know that she has so many things going on that I shouldn't expect so much of her. Realistically, it adds more stress to my day. Yesterday, she threw up because her belly was hurting so much and it just breaks my heart that we can't seem to resolve this.</p>
        <p>We are heading to Salt Lake this weekend. My husband has to work there, so we are tagging along to see family and doctors. We will be meeting with a new GI doctor there, in hopes of finding someone a little closer to us that is willing to fight for Hallie. If there ever were an emergency, Cincinnati is just too far away for us to get her to in time. She will also be having surgery while we are there. Her central line broke last week and needs to be replaced. Since we were already going to be there and the line is still functional, we decided to have her surgeon in Salt Lake perform the operation. They wil take out her old one and put a port in its place. A port is completely under the skin, so it will give her more of a normal life, allowing her to bathe and swim. We have to access it with a needle, which I am not looking forward to, but it will give her skin a break, which should help with her tape allergy. She will have her port accessed and a line attached Sunday night through Friday morning, but will have Friday, Saturday, and Sunday to be free as she calls it. We are hoping that it makes her life a little bit better.</p>
        <p>The Helping Hallie Golf Tournament is moving forward. It is July 17 at 1:30. The registration forms are up on the <a href="events.htm">Events</a> page. We are looking for sponsors, donations of items to auction off, and golfers. If you know of anyone that would be willing to help us out, please forward the information on! Thank you all so much for your continued support.</p>
]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Cincinatti Update</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1263578400</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2010 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>I know a lot of you are wondering how our trip to Cincinnati went.  Thank you all for the encouragement and support as we were out there.  The trip was really long and hard.  We spent the first week meeting with doctors, getting x-rays, a barium enema, as well as lab work.  I had forgotten how nice it is to be at a children's hospital!  The day of her enema, we had a child life specialist meet us and she treated Hallie like royalty.  She even let her choose a movie to watch in a portable DVD player during the procedure.  What a great idea!  I am going to have to remember that for when we have to do procedures here in Reno.  Child life even gave us passes to go to the museum center, which consists of the History Museum, Natural History Museum, and Children's Museum.  We were able to spend the day there the day before Derrick and Carson (our 7 year old) had to head back home.</p>
        <p>It's really emotional knowing that you are taking your child across the country to admit her, not knowing exactly what to expect.  It was hard on Hallie to travel that far and a huge eye opener for us to really see her limitations.  I am getting really good at having a Ziploc bag ready to catch her when she is throwing up.  We had to take her off of her medicine for a week to be able to really see what her intestines are capable of.  At first, she did better than we had expected, but the last few days were really rough.  She threw up so many times and was in so much pain.</p>
        <p>We are very impressed with the doctors.  They have an entire GI wing in the hospital, which is great because even the nurses were familiar with her problems and were able to give us some insight.  I was impressed with the way they had studied Hallie's case.  It took us a month to get all of her medical records out there and was a pain, but well worth it.  There is a team of 15 doctors, nurse practitioners, and dieticians that have all studied her case and we met quite a few of them.  They would come into her hospital room and ask all sorts of questions, pertaining to their specialty.  They really knew their stuff.  I felt like while they are still trying to figure her out, they had a very good grasp of why she does what she does and what direction to head in.</p>
        <p>So far, all of her test results have come back normal.  In a way it is frustrating because I know there are problems and the first doctor I talked to made it seem like because there were no issues found in the areas they tested, the rest were just fine.  I cried.  Her issues are more toward the middle of her intestines, where they weren't able to get the catheter.  After talking to one of her main doctors, he reassured me that isn't the case with her, that with her history, they were just trying to see how far up the damage went.  He is recommending that we start her on a different drug that targets more the large intestine.  We are hoping to see some improvement.  We will also be playing with her diet to try and find a good balance between what she eats, what she gets through her feeding tube and what she gets through her central line.</p>
        <p>I think the best short term benefit for us is that they helped us find tape and dressings that Hallie is not allergic to.  Changing her dressing has gone from being a nightmare, to a minor inconvenience, which is so nice!</p>
        <p>Hallie has had a cough for about 8 weeks now.  We have treated her for sinus infection, RSV, tested for pneumonia, given her steroids, pretty much everything we could think of.  We ended up at our pediatrician's right after we got back and she thinks Hallie has reflux, which is causing the coughing.  It's been a pretty rough week because the more she coughs, the more she throws up.  The more she throws up, the more acid comes up and causes her to cough more.  We have started her on prevacid and are hoping for the best.  Her poor little body is just tired and hurts all over because of this.  I am more than tired of coughing since Derrick ended up with bronchitis while we were out there and Tucker (our 1 year old) ended up with double ear infection and sinus infection.  He has now moved on to chronic rhinitis and he may end up with tonsils and adenoids being removed when he gets a little older.  I told them that I was going to move to our new house by myself and if they weren't healthy, they could stay at the old house.  None of them were big fans of that idea.</p>
        <p>We begin moving today and hope that it will be the beginning of many good changes in our lives.  I have started organizing a golf tournament for Hallie for the summer, although I have no clue what I am doing, so if any of you have any suggestions or ideas, I am more than open to them.  It will be a learning experience, but I am very excited to see what it will bring.</p>
        <p>You are all incredible.  Your words of support and encouragement mean so much.  When I get discouraged or frustrated, I go back and read them and it really helps me remember that we can do this and we will be better because of it.  Thank you, thank you, thank you!</p>
]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Happy Birthday Hallie!</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1261333800</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2009 12:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>Hallie is a big 4 years old today!  Wow!  Little did we know 4 years ago as we went to the hospital what a difficult journey lay ahead of us, but we wouldn't trade it for anything.  Hallie has taught us so much .  She is so brave and so strong.  She has the best attitude about everything, even to the point that she now is holding her own nebulizer mask (she has RSV right now) and wants to help with as much of her medicine as possible.  She is so grateful for everything.  Yesterday we celebrated Christmas early and she just thanking us for everything and telling us how "wonderful" it all was. There is rarely a day that goes by that I don't hear this little "I love you, Mommy" followed by "How many times have I told you that I love you".  She prompts tme to tell me how much I love her and that I am proud of her.  She is so quick to see the silver lining in her life.</p>
        <p>I hope each and every one of us can learn a little something from Hallie, especially this time of year.  She didn't come into this world with these problems without a purpose.  She has reached out and touched so many people, and I hope that she can continue to reach out and touch so many more.</p>
        <p>We leave in the morning for Cincinnati.  I am not looking forward to traveling with her-- it is a major undertaking in and of itself.  But we are so anxious to get her to the doctors out there.  She has been hurting so much and her intestines are just tired. There are days that she is throwing up because nothing is moving through.  There are days that she is just crying because she hurts.  She will go in on the 29th and have lab work as well as a barium enema (her bum medicine as she calls it).  We will get to meet with both Dr. Mezoff and Dr. Kaul on the 30th.  She will be admitted on January 4th and put under general anesthesia at 6:30.  They will do an endoscopy and then take out her feeding  tube in her belly and use the opening to insert wires down into her small intestine.  These have to remain in for 24 hours and will record the pressure her intestines are exerting to push food through.  It will hopefully give us an idea of how bad off her intestines really are.  She should be discharged the afternoon of the 5th.</p>
        <p>Please keep her in your prayers.  We really need to find answers and this is a difficult trip to make with her in her condition.  She has to go off all of her meds a week before she is admitted so between Christmas and New Year's is going to be rough.  We are just hoping and praying that in the end, it will be worth it and we will at least have some direction of where to go with her.</p>
        <p>Thank you for all of your kind thoughts and words of support.  This has been a very difficult year for us and we get to start the new year out by moving. The owner of the house we are living in lost his job and is having to short sell it.  We have found a new house about 5 miles north of us, which we are excited about.  We can begin moving in the middle of January, but will have to pay double rent through February, which is when our lease is up.  We just feel it is so important to get Hallie out of our current house and away from all of the prospective buyers that will be bringing who knows what germs into our home.  In the end, it will be a good change I think and help us expand our support system.  That's the way I have to look at it-- we are lsoing friends and neighbors, we are gaining the opportunity to add to the ones we already have.</p>
        <p>We hope each and every one of you has a Merry Christmas and takes time to reflect on what the holidays this time of year really mean.  They will never be the same for us since we spent Christmas 4 years ago in the hospital.  Tell your family and friends how much they mean to you.  Don't miss an opportunity to help those in need, even if it is just with a smile to someone that is looking a little down.  Kind words and a smile are sometimes all people need to get through a rough day.  You are all incredible and we appreciate so much all you do and your love and concern for Hallie and our family.</p>
]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Hallie Update</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1259703000</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 13:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>Just thought I would give you a quick Hallie update.  We took her to Stanford last month adn they have taken over her care as her primary doctors.  We have been pleased with their care so far.  I talk to her doctor at least once a week, making adjustments to her medication and dealing with all of her fun little problems.  She's developed an allergy to tape, which makes life a lot more complicated, but we have adjusted and are moving forward.</p>
        <p>Unfortunately, she is losing weight right now and is having a hard time keep her bowels moving things through, despite the fact that have have increased her TPN (nutrition through her iv).  We are taking her to Cincinnati Children's in a few weeks.  Their GI department was named America's Best Doctors in 2008, so we are very exctied to work with them.  So far, we have been very impressed and hopeful that they will be able to give us a positive direction to head in.  She will have a handful of tests done while we are out there and then we will meet with 2 of their specialists.  One deals specifically with motility (the intestines moving food through) while the other one focuses on kids with short bowel syndrom and kids that are technologically dependent.  We feel like it is a good fit and are anxious to meet with them.</p>
        <p>On to the good news.  Hallie has been approved for a wish from Make a Wish, so we will be heading to Disney World hopefully sometime in the late spring to early summer.  We are so excited about this!  From what we have heard, it will be a once in a life time trip, with them catering to her every want and need.  The thought of a relaxing vacation, where they take care of all of her medical needs while we are there is so exciting.  We will get to stay in the Give Kids the World village on Disney property.  It is a 51 acre village whith so many incredible things in and of itself.  From what I have heard from other families that have stayed there, they could have spent the whole week in the village itself.  We can hardly wait to get there!</p>
        <p>We also have heard from a player of the Cincinnati Bengals that he wants to meet Hallie, so he has gotten us tickets to a game while we are out there, as well as a VIP box to sit in so that she doesn't have to be in the cold and exposed to all of the germs.  They keep telling us this is going to be bigger than we can imagine, so we are anxious to get out there and see exactly what that means.</p>
        <p>Add all of this to the fact that we have a few companies that have adopted Hallie as their Christmas project, we are thrilled with the possibilities before us.  Thank you all for your ongoing love and support.  When we started down this road almost 4 years ago with Hallie (yes, her birthday is in a few weeks-- there were so many times that we didn't think we would get to this birthday, so we are thrilled!) we didn't realize how long and hard it would be.  It has been the most challenging thing I have ever faced.  Add to that the fact that we don't live by any family, it has been a struggle.  We appreciate all of you so much, even the ones we have never met.  Your words of support and encouragement give us the strength to keep moving forward.  We hope all of you have a very happy holiday season. Christmas has a very different meaning for us since Hallie was born and spent her first Christmas in the hospital, fighting for her life.  Cherish your family and friends and the precious moments that you have with them!  Thank you all, once again.</p>
]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Hallie Update</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1257969600</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2009 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>We have started reaching out to other hospitals in an attempt to figure out what is wrong with Miss Hallie.  We have researched for weeks and narrowed it down to Stanford and Cincinnati.  We chose bowel transplant programs, not because she is a candidate at this point, but for the fact that they see the worst of the worst and can hopefully help  us determine what is causing all of Hallies pain and motility problems.</p>
        <p>Monday, we met with Stanfords GI doctors for the first time.  They havent received all of her records and x-rays yet, so in a way it was frustrating because we are ready for action.  We are tired of the waiting game.  They increased her dose of one medicine and are putting her on an antibiotic to help ward off a bacterial overgrowth.  It sounds like she will go on an antibiotic for 2 weeks, and then off for 2 weeks, and then back on, until they figure out how to get her bowels working better.  They will see her back in 1 month.  I want to pull my hair out that we have to wait that long to see them again, but at the same time, I understand that they dont want to repeat any tests that they dont have to.</p>
        <p>They did find a sacral dimple, which could be an indicator of a nerve problem.  When we head back, they want to do a CT scan of her back and see if she has a tethered spinal cord.  At first, that idea made no sense to me.  What does her spinal cord have to do with her intestines?  Then as they started explaining that as she grows, those nerves get pulled tighter and tighter so that it is hard for the body to receive the right message that the brain sends.  They asked if she had bladder problems or was clumsy.  We said no, but later when we were talking, we remembered how hard it has been for Hallie to learn how to control her bladder.  She could have been potty trained at least a year earlier if we didnt have to worry about that.  So, the more we think about it, the more it seems to fit.  I am not pinning all of my hopes on this diagnosis, but we are  hopeful.  It would require neurosurgery to fix it, but for the first time ever, a surgery might could actually solve her problems, not just manage the damage being done.</p>
        <p>They also had some other tests they want to do, including a manometry test, which tests the pressure her lower intestines exert.  There are some different drugs they brought up, that target more specific parts of the intestines than the ones she is on, so we may be changing up her drug regimen as well.  In all, we are very hopeful that we are on the right track finally.  We are still pursuing going to Cincinnatis Childrens Hospital and are working with them to get all of Hallies medical records so that when we get out there, they will have everything that they need to help pinpoint the problems.  Hope is a pretty powerful drug and for now, we are very happy to have been given some of it!</p>
]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Here We Go Again</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1253223000</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2009 14:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>Hallie is currently sitting in a hospital bed, painting a magic wand, while we wait for surgery later today. She is wearing her Helping Hallie t-shirt and watching Cinderella. She was supposed to have surgery early this morning, so they admitted her last night, but due to a few miscommunications, she will be going in at 6:00 tonight. So far, it's been a really long day, trying to get her to understand why she still can't have anything to eat.</p>
        <p>They will be surgically implanting a central line into her chest. It will empty right above her heart so that they can begin giving her TPN throughout. TPN is basically nutrition through an iv. It is really hard on the veins, though, and since hers are so fragile to begin with, the long term solution is the central line.</p>
        <p>She has been having a lot of problems with her intestines the last few months, so the hope is that by bypassing the digestive system and putting some of her nutrients into her bloodstream, it will allow her intestines to rest and hopefully start functioning more effeciently.</p>
        <p>Hallie will still continue to use her feeding tube in her stomach 4 days a week, but the other 3 days, she will be hooked up for 12 hours to the TPN at night. This is just a starting point, until we figure out how her body will respond to this treatment and make the necessary adjustments.</p>
        <p>This means no swimming for Hallie, no baths (sponge baths are going to be our main means of keeping her clean). It means 2 more pumps to add to her iv pole, and another scar on her chest. Hopefully, 12 hours a day will be enough because when she was on it before, we were doing it 18 hours a day, which means we get to tote everything around in a back pack to provide us with some time away from home. What this means for me is being extremely vigilant to make sure that everything is clean and sterilized before and after hooking her up. She is very susceptible to line infections, so I will be scrubbing everything before mixing the TPN and making sure every nook and cranny on the port is clean before hooking her up. It also means that I will get to be mixing her TPN at night. Once mixed, it is only good for 24 hours, so the home health company will be delivering the bags without some of the ingredients, so that I can get a week's worth at a time. We were given a mini fridge at the yard sale that we chose to keep in order to have a place to keep her medicine separate from our food and daily use. All of it will have to be refrigerated. She will also be put on lipids, which is basically her main source of fat. Hopefully, she will start to gain weight again and regain some of her energy.</p>
        <p>Hallie will be in the hospital over night as they start her on the TPN and make sure that she tolerates it. Tomorrow, I will get a crash refresher course in how to care for everything at home and her first delivery of medicine should arrive in the afternoon.</p>
        <p>We have also opted to switch her from the Pediasure to a formula where the nutrients are broken down, so that it is easier for her to digest. Unfortunately, it is not available in Reno, so we will have to have it shipped in.</p>
        <p>She will also be starting an a probiotic. It will encourage good bacteria to grow in her intestines, to try and combat the overgrowth of bacteria there. The overgrowth is essentially like putting yeast in a balloon with a little sugar and water. As the bacteria multiplies, it starts to stretch out her intestines and causes them to not be able to function as well. We hope to get that under control to help ease some of her pain.</p>
        <p>Please keep Hallie in your thoughts and prayers the next few days as we adjust to this new twist in her life. Our lives will be changing to accomodate her needs and everyone of us in our family will be effected. If you have not had a chance, please check out her website. We very much need to raise more money in order to meet her new expenses. Thank you all for your love and support. It is what is getting us through all of this-- the Lord is answering our prayers through you.</p>
]]>
      </description>

    </item>

    <item>
      <title>What a Success!</title>
      <author>Necia Munro</author>

      <link>http://www.helpinghallie.com/updates.htm</link>

      <guid>1252213200</guid>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2009 22:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>
  <![CDATA[
        <p>Thank you all to your incredible support in helping us get the word out about our benefit yard sale that we did for Hallie. What started as a small thing to maybe earn enough money to take her back to Salt Lake for some tests turned into something more than we could ever have dreamed of! We are just finishing up loading the tables and everything that my husband's company lent us (thank you Freeman!). It has been a long month of sorting, organizing, and pricing, as well as living with all of the donations in my house and garage, but well worth it in the end. We surpassed our goals time and time again. So thank you to everyone for your help and support!</p>
        <p>We have had many people ask us how we managed to pull something of this magnitude off and I had to tell them that we have an incredible support system. From those that have donated financially, to those that have donated items for us to sell, as well as those that have donated their time, and for those that have sent us kind words that have lifted our spirits that day-- THANK YOU! YOU ARE THE BEST!</p>
]]>
      </description>

    </item>


    </channel>
</rss>
